The future is worth fighting for.
Dawn of the Planet of the Apes is a science fiction,
action, drama film directed by Matt Reeves.
A group of scientists in San Francisco struggle to stay alive in the aftermath of a plague that is wiping out
humanity, while Caesar tries to maintain dominance over his community of intelligent apes.
Caesar, played by Andy Serkis.
Malcolm, played by Jason Clarke.
Koba, played by Toby Kebbell.
Dreyfus, played by Gary Oldman.
Ellie, played by Keri Russell.
Alexander, played by Kodi Smit-McPhee.
Dawn of the Planet of the Apes is a 2014 American science fiction action film directed by Matt
Reeves and written by Mark Bomback and the writing team of Rick Jaffa and Amanda Silver.
The sequel to Rise of the Planet of the Apes (2011), it is the second installment in
the Planet of the Apes reboot film series and the eighth film overall.
It stars Andy Serkis as Caesar, alongside Jason Clarke, Gary
Oldman, Keri Russell, Toby Kebbell and Kodi Smit-McPhee.
The film takes place in 2026, 10 years after the events of Rise and follows a group of human survivors as they battle to stay alive in the wake of a deadly
pandemic, while Caesar tries to maintain control over his expanding ape community which could lead to an all-out war between apes and humans.
A sequel to Rise of the Planet of the Apes was announced in 2011, with the
return of both Serkis and Rupert Wyatt confirmed that November.
Wyatt departed the film in September 2012, and Reeves was
hired as his replacement that October.
Casting took place between February and March 2013, with none of
the additional original main cast members returning.
Principal photography commenced that April and lasted until that July, with filming
locations including Campbell River, Vancouver Island, and New Orleans.
The apes were created using visual effects and motion capture as commissioned by Weta Digital, with the film
featuring greater use of these components during action sequences and to create other animals.
Dawn of the Planet of the Apes premiered on June 26, 2014, at the Palace of Fine Arts in San
Francisco and was theatrically released worldwide by 20th Century Fox on July 11.
The film received positive reviews from critics and grossed over $710 million, making it the
eighth-highest-grossing film of 2014 and the highest-grossing film in the franchise.
It also received numerous awards and nominations, including an
Academy Award nomination for Best Visual Effects.
The sequel, War for the Planet of the Apes, was released in 2017.
The film explores themes of san francisco, california,
peace, solidarity, gorilla, intelligence.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.